<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul W. Hook</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Paul W. Hook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scraping bioRxiv</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/10/2018-02-27-scraping-biorxiv-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/10/2018-02-27-scraping-biorxiv-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first of a series focusing on tracking preprints on bioRxiv. The motivation behind this and a more detailed explanantion can be found here.
Scraping in R When I began to approach preprint tracking, the mysterious world of &amp;ldquo;HTML scraping&amp;rdquo; seemed like something that would help. Simply, scraping allows you to extract information from the underlying HTML (Hypertext Markup Language) documents that make up websites.
HTML scraping seemed like a good idea for preprint tracking because: A) It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like there are simple/easy ways to access a bioRxiv database that holds such information (especially for someone with limited experience in this like me) and B) Whether or not the paper is published in a peer-reviewed journal is displayed clearly on each preprint&amp;rsquo;s page (see below on the webpage in red).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping track of preprints</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/04/2018-02-25-scraping-biorxiv-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/04/2018-02-25-scraping-biorxiv-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Premise For my first set of blog posts, I have decided to start a series about preprints. Awhile ago, an interesting question was brought up by Shannon Ellis in her wonderful blog post &amp;ldquo;Let there be preprint citations!&amp;quot; (emphasis is mine):
Problem #2: Preprints often become peer-reviewed research. How will we keep track?
Solution #2a (if this occurs during while the manuscript is being drafted): It is up to the author(s) to ensure that their manuscript is as up to date as possible upon submission for publication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first blog post!</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/04/02/2018-02-20-my-first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/2018/04/02/2018-02-20-my-first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello! If you haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to tell by the website already, my name is Paul Hook.
I am a fourth year Ph.D. student in the Human Genetics program in the McKusick-Nathans Institute of Genetic Medicine at the Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine. I am in Dr. Andy McCallion&amp;rsquo;s lab.
You can learn a little more about me here, so I won&amp;rsquo;t go on and on in the inaugural blog post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! My name is Paul Hook. I am a Postdoctoral Fellow in Dr. Winston Timp&amp;rsquo;s lab in the Department of Biomedical Engineering at Johns Hopkins University. I received my PhD from the Human Genetics program in the McKusick-Nathans Institute of Genetic Medicine at the Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine. I did my thesis work in Dr. Andy McCallion&amp;rsquo;s lab. There I focused on trying to elucidate the genetics that underlie Parkinson disease and schizophrenia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description> Email me: phook2 [at] jhmi.edu I&amp;rsquo;m on Twitter/X: @pwhook Find my code and analyses on Github Check me out on Google Scholar </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/</guid>
      <description>Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante. Donec eu libero sit amet quam egestas semper. Aenean ultricies mi vitae est. Mauris placerat eleifend leo.
1. WHAT TO DO IF I HAVE STILL NOT RECEIVED THE ORDER? Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum tortor quam, feugiat vitae, ultricies eget, tempor sit amet, ante.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>papers</title>
      <link>/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/papers/</guid>
      <description>Postdoc 2023 Volkel, K.D, Lin, K.N., Hook, P.W., Timp, W., Keung, A.J., and Tuck, J.M (2023). FrameD: framework for DNA-based data storage design, verification, and validation. Bioinformatics, Volume 39, Issue 10, October 2023, btad572. https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/btad572
Rhie, A., Nurk, S., Cechova, M., Hoyt, S.J., Taylor, D.J., Altemose, N., Hook, P.W., Koren, S., Rautiainen, M., Alexandrov, I.A., …, Eichler, E.E, O&amp;rsquo;Neill, R., Schatz, M.C., Miga, K.H., Makova, K.D., and Phillippy, A.M. (2023).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/</guid>
      <description>T2T epigenetics changes changes Analysis of public mouse ATAC-seq data Github: https://github.com/pwh124/open_chromatin
Data: This Github repo and Zenodo data repo are associated with Hook and McCallion, 2020
Single-cell RNA-seq of dopaminergic neurons Github: https://github.com/pwh124/sc-da-parkinsons
This Gitub repo contains code for analyses and figures associated with Hook, et al., 2018
Website: https://pwh124.github.io/sc-da-parkinsons/
I created this website from the Github repo above using the workflowr package. I wanted to create this website so that my data would be more accessible and reproducible.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
