<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biorxiv on Paul Hook</title>
    <link>/categories/biorxiv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biorxiv on Paul Hook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/biorxiv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping bioRxiv</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/27/2018-02-27-scraping-biorxiv-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/27/2018-02-27-scraping-biorxiv-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Scraping bioRxiv This post is the first of a series focusing on tracking preprints on bioRxiv. The motivation behind this and a more detailed explanantion can be found here
scraping in R When I first began to approach preprint tracking, the mysterious world of “HTML scraping” seemed like something that would help. Scraping seemed like a good idea because: A) It doesn’t seem like there are simple/easy ways to access a bioRxiv database that holds such information and B) Whether or not the paper is published is displayed clearly on each preprint’s page (see below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping track of preprints</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/25/2018-02-25-scraping-biorxiv-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/25/2018-02-25-scraping-biorxiv-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Premise For my first set of blog posts, I have decided to start a series about preprints. Awhile ago, an interesting question was brought up by Shannon Ellis in her wonderful blog post “Let there be preprint citations!” (emphasis is mine):
 Problem #2: Preprints often become peer-reviewed research. How will we keep track?
Solution #2a (if this occurs during while the manuscript is being drafted): It is up to the author(s) to ensure that their manuscript is as up to date as possible upon submission for publication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>